孩子们好  现在播出的是
Ahoy, kids, it's time for
海绵宝宝如你所愿精品特辑
SpongeBob's "You Wish" Spectacular Special
如你所愿
万岁
Hurray
现在有请如你所愿的主持人
And now the host of "You Wish"
他有着比基德船长更蓬松的灯笼裤
He's got puffier pantaloons than Captain Kidd
有着比黑胡子更卷的胡须
and fuzzier facial hair than Blackbeard
他就是全美最爱的海盗
He's America's favorite pirate
恩斯诺的派斯
Patchy of Encino
你们好  粉丝同伴们
Ahoy, fellow fanatics
欢迎来到我家
Welcome to me quarters
要不你们来厨房吧
Why don't you come on back to the galley
我今天在给你们整点消遣的
I'm cooking up a real treat for you today
打进来投出票时间到
It's calling-in vote time
你们今天来选择我们动画片的结局
You get to choose how our cartoon ends today
可以用电话来
via the phone
或者用互联网来
or the Internet
只要你们有这么个技术条件
if you're technologically inclined
现在这部动画片跟大多动画片不一样
Now, this cartoon is different from most cartoons
不一样在
in that
怎么个不一样法
In what way?
这不就是我的没意思小跟班
Well, if it isn't my less-than-amusing sidekick
鹦鹉波蒂吗
Potty the parrot
波蒂  跟观众们打个招呼
Potty, say hello to the nice people
救命
Help
我是被强行关押在这的
I'm being held here against my will
救命
Help
波蒂快回来
Potty, come back
波蒂
Potty?
Potty
你哪去了
Where'd you go?
波蒂
Potty?
你在里面吗  兄弟
You in there, buddy?
波蒂
Potty?
Potty
放我出去  你个坏鸟
Get me out of here, you scurvy bird
我刚刚说到哪了
Now, what was I saying?
这部动画片不像是
Now, this cartoon ain't like
你们看的那种旱鸭子版动画片
most of your "landlubbing" cartoons
这部动画片不止有一个
This cartoon has not one
也不止有两个
not two
而是三个不同的结局
but three different endings
等我让你们拨打
So, when I tell you to call
屏幕下方滚动的电话号码
the number that's scrolling down there
at the bottom of the screen
不好意思  原版电话号码
去戴维琼斯柜子里安度晚年了
现在还不行
No, not now
让你们打了才能打
Don't call till I tell you to
播动画片
Roll the cartoon
记得要在最后投票  因为
Now, remember, to vote at the end because
非得不让我好过是吧
You're not gonna make this easy, are you?
安静
Quiet
快停下  晩点再响起来
Avast there, belay that ringing
别响了
Stop
要让我疯掉了
It's driving me mad
骗上贼船
导演
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海草哥麦片
Kelpo
内含八个奖品之一
"With one of eight essential prizes inside"
真是见鬼了
Holy Shrimp
章鱼哥
Squidward
上天从我麦片盒里生小孩了
The sky had a baby from my cereal box
章鱼哥
Squidward
上天生小孩了
The sky had a baby
那个不是小孩  是大锚
That's not a baby, that's a giant anchor
现在给我滚
Now, go away
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
上天生小孩了
The sky had a baby
我知道
I know
你说该给人家起什么名
What do you think we should name it?
要么
How about?
要不你们两个去爬锚绳去
Why don't you two go climb its anchor rope?
它一定会通往很远的地方去
I'm sure it goes somewhere far away
看看你们干的好事
Now look what you've done
不是我们干的  章鱼哥
We didn't do it, Squidward
我们可清白了
Our hands are clean
清白
Clean
我倒要刨根问底查个明白
Well, I'm going to get to the bottom of this thing
那不是问顶吗
Wouldn't that be the top?
章鱼哥  等等
Squid, wait
章鱼哥
Squidward
几英寸后
船
Ship
海绵宝宝  你到底要胡思乱想多久
SpongeBob, how long are you going to stay
in your little fantasy world?
不是  快看
No, look
真的有大船
a giant ship
太棒了  我们走
Great, let's go
终于能给这乱扔大锚的来一点教训了
Now I can finally give this anchor-dropper
a piece of my mind
感觉不太好  章鱼哥
I don't know, Squidward
那艘船周围有可怕的绿光
That ship has a spooky green glow around it
可能就是因为
That's probably because
船主实在是游手好闲
its good-for-nothing owner is too lazy
懒得打扫  锚也不好好放
to clean or drop his anchors in the right place
章鱼哥  等等
Squid, wait
谁是这木头箱子的主人
All right, who owns this crate?
主人
快出来
Come on out
我要投诉你
I want to file a complaint
这地方是不是感觉很熟悉
Doesn't this place seem familiar?
不清楚
I don't know
怎么了
why?
不好说
l don't know
响 铃
感觉就是有那么点印象
Doesn't it just kind of ring a bell?
没错
Yes
我知道谁是这船的主人
I know who owns this boat
就是想不起名字
I just can't place the name
飞天魔鬼所有
错了  名字不叫
No, no, it's not
我是飞天魔鬼
I am the Flying Dutchman
对了
That's it
章鱼哥  这船是红男爵的
This ship belongs to the Red Baron
是谁胆敢在飞天魔鬼的地盘打扰人家
Who be disturbing the Flying Dutchman in his own lair?
是章鱼哥
lt's Squidward
他要投诉你
He wants to complain to you
我我我
I-I-I
我可可可没有
No, I-I-I don't
那你骂人家船脏人懒又是怎么一回事
Well, what about all that stuff about him
having a dirty ship and being lazy and all?
我可没说过
I-I never said that
侮辱一个人的船
Insulting a man's ship
比侮辱一个人的妈更严重
be worse than insulting his mother
错了  等下
No, no, wait
你刚骂的是他妈脏
it was his mother you said was dirty
不是船脏
not his ship
下一个是你们
You're next
真是差一点就死了
That was a close one
欢迎回来
Welcome back
真是差一点点就死了
That was a closer one
欢迎回来
Welcome back
他们两个怎么每次捣乱
How come when they act up
你都要欢迎
all they get is the welcome wagon?
要我说  早就
If you ask me, it's
所以你们要不要再来一次
So are you going to try that again?
也许吧
Probably
那现在呢
How about now?
不对  他们不要
No, no, they're not
听好了
Now listen
鬼矩手册
无论是谁登上了飞天魔鬼的船
"Whosoever sets foot on the Flying Dutchman's ship
不管是不是不请自来
"uninvited or otherwise
都要成为他的鬼水手  一辈子
"shall become members of his ghostly crew forever
然后
and, uh
永远
ever"
我们会领名片吗
Will we be getting business cards?
别吵
Silence
你们现在是我的鬼水手了
You're part of my crew now
我们的工作就是四处航行吓唬别人
and our job is to sail around and frighten people
会很累人  麻木人
lt'll be grueling, mind-numbing
还反反复复的
and repetitive
差不多就像
Just like
白天的电视节目
daytime television
现在你给我听好  先生
Now, you listen here, mister
你要是真觉得我会
If you think I'm going to
在这垃圾堆里待个五分钟以上
spend more than five minutes on this dumpster
你就想多了
then you're crazy
倒是看看这地方
I mean, look at this place
恶心死了
It's disgusting
是谁教你
Whoever told you
一定要把油灯放硬木板边上
that hanging oil lamps
next to hardwood paneling was a good idea
怎么
Now what?
要给我看东西
I suppose you're going to show me
真是好好看
Gee, that's very nice
这什么玩意  魔术表演吗
What is this, some kind of magic act?
谁还要进去飞天绝望里玩一玩
Would anyone else like to enter the Fly of Despair?
不用了
No
我们明白自己地位了  飞天魔鬼先生
we know our place now, Mr. Dutchman
我们会照你说的做的
We'll do anything you say
那么你们俩新来的可以  擦甲板
Then for starters, you can swab the deck
快看  派大星
Look, Patrick
活生生的鬼拖把
a real, live ghost mop
我有这顶帽子
And I got this hat
听着
Listen
我们今晚要去裤头村
We're heading down to Bikini Bottom tonight
来闹个鬼
for a little haunting spree
所以我要这艘船的外观非常吓人
so I want this ship to look good and scary
你是说你要船的外观非常
You mean you want it to look good
吓人
and scary
我们也许可以
Well, I think we could probably
错了
No, no
人家说的是要外观特别好
I think he means he wants it to look so good
好到可怕的地步
that it's scary
或者可能是让船的外观很吓人
Or maybe that by looking so scary
就可以忽略掉船很难看了
you forget that it doesn't look good
我听不懂
I don't get it
很简单的
Look, it's easy
意思就是
It simply means
别管什么意思了
Never mind what it means
样子吓人就行
I just want it to look scary
仅此而已
That's it
就是那种
You know
天花板发霉  水池里有虫爬的
mold growing on the ceilings, bugs in the sink
所以你不要船好看吗
So, you don't want it to look good?
快点干
Get moving
水手的命儿真是妙
A sailor's life is a wonderful life
命儿实在妙
A wonderful life for sure
今晚夜色真美
What a night be this
水手们  跟我嚎叫
Crew, howl with me
让七大洋颤栗吧
so that we might set the seven seas ablaze with fear
可以了
That'll do
好了  方家伙
Okay, square one
既然粉家伙在负责航行
Since pink one's working the navigation
就让你来找我们第一个受害者
it's up to you to find our first victim
给  用这把望远镜找
Here, use this spyglass
动作快
Now, hurry up
时间不等人
We're burning moonlight
看看能找到谁
Let's see who we can find
船长  那边那位可以吓
Captain, there's a guy we can scare
我有四块饼干  吃掉了一个
I had four biscuits, and I ate one
就只有三块了
Then I only had three
看到有小孩子夜不归宿让我开心死了
It does me heart good to see children out after dark
粉家伙  给我们带到石头后边去
Pink one, take us behind those rocks
到石头后边去
Moving behind the rocks
开走
Keep going
很好  很好
You're good, you're good
再
And
停
stop
放心  船长
Don't worry, Cap'n
我们会把划痕弄干净的
We'll buff out those scratches
好了  那个别管了
All right, never mind it
我给暗号你们就跳出来
Just jump out when I give the signal
做好准备
Prepare to be burdened
让我的鬼海盗们留下挥之不去的阴影
with the haunting memory of my ghostly ghost pirates
暗号就那
Was that the signal?
好的  抱歉抱歉
Okay, sorry, sorry
再来一遍
Just do it again
让我的鬼海盗们留下挥之不去的阴影
With the haunting memory of my ghostly ghost pirates
怎么做到的
How does he do that?
快回船上去
Get back on the ship
这还是个谜
It's still a mystery
那些人真是笨蛋
Those guys are dorks
对  不过是我的笨蛋
Yes, but they're my dorks
很好  很好
You're good, you're good
很好
You're good
很好  很好
You're good, you're good
你觉得飞天魔鬼干嘛
Why do you think the Dutchman
叫我们在卧铺里等啊
asked us to wait in our bunk room?
可能是他要给我们奖励
Maybe he's going to give us a reward
比如说电影票吗
Like movie passes?
或者是超大咖啡杯
Or an oversized coffee mug
经过考虑
I've been thinking
别跳了
Stop bouncing
让你们一辈子当我船员好像行不通
This whole "crew for eternity" thing isn't working out
与其说是你们的问题  不如说是我的
It's not really you, so much as it is me
你要放了我们吗
You're setting us free?
其实吧  我要吃掉你们
Well, actually, I'm just going to eat you
晩餐见
See you at dinner
等等
Wait
我有个办法
I have an idea
真的吗
Really?
是什么
What is it?
逃走吧
Let's leave
可是门锁上了
But the door is locked
唯一的出路是穿过
And the only way out is through the
香水商店
perfume department
就这么干了
Let's do it
我讨厌从那走
I always hate going in there
没错
Yeah
等等  你听
Wait, listen
亲爱的日记
Dear Diary
我跟他们讲我明天要吃掉他们
l've told them I'm going to eat them tomorrow
我做了那种棕酱
l made up some of that brown sauce
先前我表哥临时给我看过
my cousin showed me just for the occasion
又找着我的饭点袜了  可真是好事
It's a good thing I found my dining sock again
还记得我上次丢了饭点袜不
Remember the last time I lost me dining sock?
当时我一整个星期都吃不下饭
I couldn't eat for a whole week
是啊  有时我在想要是碰巧出了事
Yes, sir, sometimes I wonder how I survive
我还怎么好好过日子
If anything should ever happen
把我袜子还回来
Give me back my sock
大家都清楚我没袜子吃不下饭
Everyone knows I can't eat without it
不给
Never
那好
Okay, then
给我
Give it to me
不给
No
等等
Wait
你会把弹性拉没的
You're stretching out the elastic
好像陷入僵局了
It would seem we have reached an impasse
粉家伙说得对
Pink one is right
跟你们说
Tell you what
你们把袜子还我  我就给你们
you give me back the sock and I'll give you
三个愿望
three wishes
要五个
Make it five
四个
Four
三个
Three
不要就拉倒
Take it or leave it
好吧
Okay
三个
three
你们有三个愿望
You get three wishes
有三个愿望  派大星
Three wishes, Pat
是不是很棒啊
Isn't that great?
愿望
Wishes?
真希望能早点知道
I wish we had known that earlier
好了  你们就剩下两个愿望了
Okay, you got two wishes left
好啦  还有两个
Well, we still have two more
好激动啊
How exciting
真希望章鱼哥能来亲眼目睹
I wish Squidward were here to see this
真高兴一切都结束了
Boy, I'm glad all that's over
章鱼哥  你回来了
Squidward, you're back
你猜怎么着
Guess what
飞天魔鬼给了我们三个愿望
The Dutchman gave us three wishes
派大星用了第一个
Patrick used the first one
我好像
and I guess I
用掉了第二个
just used the second one
那么最后一个是你们欠我的
Well, then the last one you owe me
因为你们又把我拖下水了
because you got me back into this mess
慢着  愿望应该是我的
Wait, I think it belongs to me
都够了
That's enough
用我的神秘超凡力量
Using my mystic otherworldly powers
由我来决定最后一个愿望归谁
I shall decide who gets the last wish
咿呢咪呢唛呢哞  抓住水手脚趾头
Eenie-meenie-minie-mo, catch a sailor by the toe
如果大叫放他走
If he hollers, let him go
我妈教导我要挑最好的那个
My mother told me to pick the very best one and
投票
全体成员
All hands
投票
投票时间到
Time to vote
投票
现在来投票
It's voting time
投票
好了  动画片先播到这里
Well, that's our cartoon so far
现在让你们来决定结局
Now it's time for you to decide how it ends
最后一个愿望会花落谁家呢
Who will get their last wish
会是轻狂的章鱼哥
Will it be sassy Squidward
还是肥肥的派大星
Portly Patrick
还是好家伙海绵宝宝呢
or good old SpongeBob?
我忠心的船员正热切等候你们的来电
My trusty crew is eagerly awaiting your call
不好意思  原版电话号码
去戴维琼斯柜子里安度晚年了
快把沙发上的锚拉起来
So hoist your anchor off that couch
速速开始投票
and make with the votin'
现在正是大好时机
This is your big chance
广告过后马上揭晓胜利者
We'll be right back to announce the winner
孩子们好  我回来了
Ahoy, children, I'm back
希望你们大家都把票投出去了
I hope all you boys and girls got your votes in
因为你们现在必须走甲板落海身亡了
because it's time for you to walk the plank
请稍候
抱歉  孩子们
Sorry, kids
我想说的是
What I meant to say was
现在要来公布胜利者了
it's time to announce the winner
不过首先  来看看落选的结局
But first, let's take a look
at the endings you didn't choose
根据我们的高科计数器上写的
According to our high-tech counterology
落选的有  派大星
you didn't choose Patrick
还是先来看看要是派大星中选
But let's see what Patrick would have wished for
会许什么愿吧
if you'd picked him
好  播录像带
Okay, roll the tape
播录像带
Roll the tape
roll the tape
播录
roll
天啊
Oh, God
我妈教导我要挑最好的那个
My mother told me to pick the very best one and
就
you
你
are
了
it
选到你了  派大星
That's you, Patrick
快许愿
Make your wish
等等  派大星听着
Wait, Patrick, listen
我可不太想
I do not particularly feel like
一辈子都困在这里
being trapped here for all eternity
一辈子是一段非常长的时间
Eternity is a very long time
懂吗
Understand?
派大星  一定要使劲想
Patrick, you've got to think harder
加倍努力使出吃奶的劲想
than you've ever thought before
那样没用
That's not gonna do it
再使劲想
Think harder
加油派大星
Come on, Patrick
对  快想
Yeah, think, think
使劲去想  加油
Put on your thinking cap, come on
对  你也能行的
Yeah, you can do it, too
加油  派大星
come on, Patrick
好  我许好愿了
Okay, I got it
你的愿望实现了
Your wish is granted
对不起了
I'm sorry
要点口香糖吗
Want some gum?
你许愿要口香糖
You wished for gum?
要是非得一辈子待在这里
Well, if we're gonna be here forever
倒不如让口气清新清新一下
we might as well have fresh breath
拜托  飞天魔鬼先生
Come on, Mr. Dutchman
放我们出去吧
let us out
别这么坏
Don't be so mean
有薄荷味
Minty
拜托放我们出去
Come on let us out
那派大星可让我震惊到假腿都在震了
That Patrick shivers me timbers
right down to my peg leg
不选那个结局还挺对的  孩子们
You were right not to pick that one, kids
简直就是胡扯  废话一通
Seemed like a lot of nonsense to me, malarkey
好了  来看看另一个落选者吧
Oh, well, let's take a look at the other loser
看来章鱼哥也落选了
It appears you didn't vote for Squidward
没怪你们
l don't blame you
我也不会投他
I wouldn't have either
但还是先来看看如果飞天魔鬼
But let's see what would have happened
if the old Dutchman's
点到了章鱼哥会怎么样吧
meenie-minie-mo finger landed on Squidward
就
You
你
are
了
it
章鱼哥  你有愿望了
Squidward, you get a wish
超棒的大愿望
A great big wish
没错  知道我要许什么愿吗
That's right, and you know what I wish?
不知道
No
我希望我从前一生都没
I wish that I had never met
见过你们两个呆头
you two barnacleheads before in my entire life
如你所愿
Show me it
你好  貌似我们以前没见过
Hi, there, I don't believe we've met
我叫海绵宝宝
My name is SpongeBob
这是我同伴派大星
and this is my associate Patrick
嗨
Hi
那不是我的意思
That's not what I meant
好了  既然你们互相介绍完了
Well, now that introductions are out of the way
那么就开饭了
it's time for dinner
你刚说你叫什么名字
And what did you say your name was?
我是章鱼哥
l'm Squidward
你邻居
I'm your neighbor
很高兴认识你  章鱼哥
Nice to meet you, Squidward
我看我们会有好多时间互相熟悉了
We'll have plenty of time to get
to get to know each other, I guess
现在就是万众期待的时刻
And now, the moment you've all been waiting for
准备好把牛奶从鼻子里喷出来吧
So, get ready to blow milk out your nose
因为现在要公布胜利者了
'cause it's time to announce the winner
信封拿来  波蒂
The envelope, please, Potty
谢谢你  我的乖鸟助理
Thank you, my fine-feathered assistant
真想不到啊
Well, what do you know?
胜利者是
The winner is
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
胜利者
波蒂  闻到什么了没
Hey, Potty, you smell something?
波蒂  你脑袋装了引信
Potty, that fuse in your head
都说过不耍特技了
I told you, we're not doing that stunt
我没收到备忘录
I didn't get the memo
现在是万众强推的结局
And now the most requested ending
万岁
Hooray
就
You
你
are
了
it
现在快想  海绵宝宝
Now, think, SpongeBob
我们就要被吃掉了
We're about to get eaten
你可以许什么愿望
What can you wish for
可以让我们不被吃掉
to make it so we don't get eaten?
放心  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我都想明白了
I've got it all figured out
他不会吃掉我们的
He won't be able to eat us
因为我希望飞天魔鬼是吃素的
because I wish that the Dutchman was a vegetarian
万岁
Hooray
我们回家了
We're home
成功了  海绵宝宝
You did it, SpongeBob
我们安全了
We're safe
可我们为什么变水果了
But why have we been turned into fruits?
我也许了个愿
I get a wish, too
水果可以预防坏血病
And fruit prevents scurvy
快给我回来
Get back here with that
我要逮着你们
I'll get you
等下
Hold on
对不起  孩子们
Sorry about that, kids
只是派斯忍不住了
lt's just that old Patchy can't help
节目最后哽咽到说不出话来
but get all choked up at the end of a show
不过好消息就是  从现在起
But the good news is, from now on
你们像通常那样看旱鸭子版的
when you watch this cartoon "landlubbing" style
这部动画片的时候
like you usually do
就会有你们选到的结局了
it'd have the ending you picked
现在你们就是成功的正式动画策划了
So, now you're an official
big-time cartoon decision-maker
可别冲昏头了
Just don't let it go to your head
好了  波蒂来跟大家说晩安
Yup, say good night to the folks, Potty
波蒂
Potty?
我不干了
I quit
节目就到这了
Well, that's it, folks
我得马上去办员工管理工作了
Right now I've got a little
employee management to take care of
波蒂
Oh, Potty?
波蒂  快进你的好笼子吧
Potty, get in your nice cage
才不进
I don't think so
于是
And so
海绵宝宝如你所愿精品特辑到此结束
we conclude SpongeBob's "You Wish" Spectacular Special
感谢投票
Thanks for voting
不行
No